<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Over Engineered</title>
    <link>https://blog.davidccunliffe.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Over Engineered</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© [David Cunliffe](https://blog.davidccunliffe.com)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 21:53:45 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.davidccunliffe.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Init</title>
      <link>https://blog.davidccunliffe.com/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 21:53:45 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.davidccunliffe.com/home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey all this is my first blog post. The concept of this blog is to educate and show a glimpse of my day to day. I hope to produce content at least weekly to get started.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Will be covering different technology aspects centered around DevOps and Cloud Services. The other will be around general automation tools and services I use to gear up for an engagement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If your interested in following along on other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://blog.davidccunliffe.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.davidccunliffe.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is David Cunliffe. Welcome to my technical blog where I&amp;rsquo;ll be discussing various projects I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on over the years.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for all sizes of companies, from small to medium business up to fortune 50 companies, ranging from DevOps deliveries up to full&#xA;blown architecture work designing large scale foundational systems within both AWS and GCP.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My passion is was networking in technology for many years. I enjoy learning about virtualization technologies such as VMware, Proxmox, Docker, and my latest adventures have been within Kubernetes. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked work closely with on-premise tech for the first part of my technology career.&#xA;Over the last decade I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my time developing my cloud based infrastructure skills to aid in the virtual world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Detailed Cloud and DevOps Experience report, 2008-</title>
      <link>https://blog.davidccunliffe.com/cloud-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 17:04:33 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.davidccunliffe.com/cloud-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a sampling of some of the projects I’ve completed in the past 10+ years.&#xA;Most of the following projects were done for large enterprises and Fortune 500 companies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Designed and built a multiple foundational builds within AWS and GCP. Utilizing various Infrastructure as Code tools, in AWS prior to Landing Zone and Control Tower. I utilized Cloudformation Stacksets to deploy resources using a account factory developed with AWS Service Catalog. Later on utilizing CDK tooling such as Landing Zone Accelerator to perform the automation at scale in a centralized pipeline. In GCP I&amp;rsquo;ve leveraged tools such as Terraform to build out custom modules along with Python to develop organizational project builds with Zero Trust access via Workload Identity pools and pipelines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hire Me</title>
      <link>https://blog.davidccunliffe.com/hire-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 16:32:08 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.davidccunliffe.com/hire-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for an AWS or GCP cloud consultant who has been in IT since 2008, ping me. I can help you with projects small, large and everything in between. Perhaps you just need to run an idea past a different set of ears and eyes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hire me &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; you&amp;rsquo;re looking for someone who is:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;an experienced pro who brings a diverse set of experiences to the table, and sees the big picture.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;an independent worker who takes initiative.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;detailed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;organized.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;plans ahead.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;easy to get along and work with.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t hire me &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; you&amp;rsquo;re looking for someone who:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Authentication of Users &amp; Apps to Google Cloud for Local Workstation Development</title>
      <link>https://blog.davidccunliffe.com/blog/2022-02-gcp-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 17:45:18 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.davidccunliffe.com/blog/2022-02-gcp-auth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are developing code (on your workstation) to interact with the Google Cloud Platform (GCP) using either the Google Cloud SDK Command Line Tools (i.e. gcloud) and/or the Google Cloud Client Libraries, then you&amp;rsquo;ll need to authenticate first.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article was inspired by the excellent explanatory &lt;a href=&#34;https://codeburst.io/google-cloud-authentication-by-example-1481b02292e4&#34;&gt;how-to article created by John Tucker&lt;/a&gt;, and is essentially a &amp;lsquo;cheat-sheet&amp;rsquo; version for that how-to.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note that this article does not cover how to authenticate when you or your proxy is inside GCP or in another environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terraform Tips and Tricks</title>
      <link>https://blog.davidccunliffe.com/blog/2021-10-terraform-tips-and-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 10:23:05 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.davidccunliffe.com/blog/2021-10-terraform-tips-and-tricks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update, Feb 2019&lt;/em&gt;: Note that with the imminent release of Terraform v0.12, some of the advice, commands, etc. in this article may not apply or work any more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having used Hashicorp&amp;rsquo;s Terraform since 2016, I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a set of tips and tricks around developing and debugging Terraform code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;version-pinning&#34;&gt;Version Pinning&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even at 4+ yrs old, Terraform is still not even at version 1.0. However, along the way even the minor releases have had major&amp;ndash;and many times breaking&amp;ndash;changes. For that reason, I&amp;rsquo;ve always strongly recommended that one pins their code to at least the minor version # (e.g. 0.11.x), and Terraform has a mechanism to do this. E.g.:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
